ORIGINAL STORY SWEET HOME
BY CARNBY KIM AND YOUNGCHAN HWANG
SEPTEMBER 2000
Why did you do it?
Who are you?
-You've grown a lot.
-Answer me.
It was just a prank.
Don't come!
Don't come, Sang-wook!
I didn't think that would happen.
It would've been nice
if it had rained like this that day.
Don't you agree?
Don't show up again.
I was already punished.
…sentenced to 11 months in prison
and 2 years of supervised probation.
Who decides that?
I hear you kill people for money.
Do you also find people?
JULY 2020
I asked him where my daughter was.
He said she was here
and gave this to me.
The bastard that kidnapped my daughter.
Look at her smiling because
she doesn't realize anything.
She asked him to take a nice picture
since it's for me.
I was going to buy pesticides with this.
I have no will to live.
Then just die.
But how can I?
That son of a bitch is still alive
and running around freely,
but I don't know where my daughter is!
Why are the police stopping me? Why?
How is that the law?
How?
Please find her.
You're the only one I can turn to now.
Please…
What is this?
Son of a bitch…
That man's a murderer!
I was already punished.
How is that the law?
You fucking murderer.
Don't touch me.
Take care of the rest on your own.
GUARD ON DUTY
Nobody's going to take it.
Gosh.
You scared me to death.
I'll pick it up for you, so give me that.
Give you what? My liver?
Are you really going to be like this?
Can't I even look at it?
You can only look.
I'll be watching you.
Do you have any left?
There's enough.
Shouldn't we kick him out?
For what reason?
For catching a murderer?
He didn't catch him. He killed him.
It was self-defense.
Yun-jae that bastard deserved to die.
If it weren't for that thug,
-one of us would've--
-So what?
He's still a murderer.
He might kill again. You never know.
It could be any one of us…
Thank you.
Right now, this is all I have…
I think I'll be joining Yun-a soon.
If you're still looking for her,
please stop.
I hope you're safe.
Thank you very much.
Why are you burning money?
I was paid to do an errand.
I failed.
Why am I here?
I'm sorry.
I saw the text message.
I THINK I'LL BE JOINING YUN-A SOON.
Not everyone agrees,
but you can stay if you want.
I don't think what you did was right.
But you did what you had to do.
FROM 7,800 WON
Can anyone…
pray?
Yes, of course.
You do it.
Why me?
Because God probably likes you
more than me.
Help!
This is just great.
Have fun.
Are they really siblings?
Was she adopted or something?
Let's call it a day.
Good work.
-Lower it.
-Okay.
Slowly.
JUNE 2020
Are you finished?
Yes, I checked it thoroughly
because I like you.
How is the condition?
Well…
It's pretty okay for such an old building.
When do you get off work?
Let's have dinner together.
I wish we could.
Do you only go home to Seoul once a month?
They're working you too hard.
I'm sorry.
What can I do?
You look sexy when you work,
so I'll let it slide.
CHIEF PHYSICIAN NAM SANG-WON
What's "Crucru"?
Is it your blog? It's logged in.
Hey, Yi-kyung.
Well…
When is it?
Our wedding photo shoot?
What?
What's this? You're acting suspiciously.
-What?
-What are you hiding?
Did you write you don't want
to get married?
No, it's nothing like that.
Yi-kyung.
It's nothing like that. Yi-kyung.
You do as you please, don't you?
Please leave.
What?
What are you saying?
We need your help, a firefighter's help.
But you seem preoccupied.
Thanks for telling me to leave.
No, Yi-kyung.
-You shouldn't.
-There's something I need to do.
Thanks for everything.
You look better as a monster.
So becoming a monster is your dream?
Why do you try so hard?
I work hard at everything.
When monsters do show up,
we'll all be killed.
Trying hard won't stop that.
I look forward to your turn.
Me? I won't do it. Do you think I'm crazy?
Yes. You're a crazy bitch.
That's why you'll end up doing it.
And you'll work
even harder than me.
Gosh, my precious baby.
Don't ride it too hard.
Be gentle!
Why did you poke your nose in?
To pay off a debt.
What do you mean?
Why would you pay it off with my bike?
God isn't like that.
He doesn't just listen to the prayers
of those He likes more.
What are you trying to do?
Soju is too bitter if you drink it alone.
And you end up drinking too much.
I used to be an alcoholic.
I'm desperately resisting
the urge to drink.
I realized that
what you see isn't everything.
People,
the world,
and God's will, too.
I fought by praying.
I'm sure you had your own method.
You're in charge of this place now.
Why would I do that?
Try to fight in a different way.
This is a good place to be alone.
Oh, right.
Now that you're in charge…
Save the rest of that.
You're cheating.
Stop playing with toys.
Read a book.
I'M NOT AFRAID OF THE DARK
Well,
Yeong-su can't read yet.
Hey,
kids your age in Gangnam
can speak Chinese.
Open the book.
All right.
I'M NOT AFRAID OF THE DARK
-"I'm
not afraid
-of the
-of the…"
dark."
You try.
-"Dark."
Again.
GREEN HOME RULES OF SURVIVAL
QUARANTINE THE INFECTED
ONE. MOVE IN GROUPS OF TWO OR MORE.
KIM YEONG-SU
BUDDY SYSTEM LIST
LEE EUN-YU, YOON JI-SU
LEE EUN-HYEOK, SEO YI-KYUNG
What? My name isn't on it.
Mine isn't on it, either.
You can be my buddy.
With you?
Yes.
Because…
we're secret agents.
Green Home rules of survival.
One. Move in groups of two or more.
Report anything unusual immediately.
Two. Eat once a day.
Only the prescribed amount is distributed.
What is this?
You call this a rice ball?
It should be at least this big.
Thirty-six point six.
Your temperature is normal.
What about that dog? Can't it change, too?
Three. Check everyone's temperature
every night at 8 p.m.
Thank you.
Quarantine the infected.
Did you shut down the elevator?
We're running out of power
and it's dangerous,
so we'll run it in case of emergency only.
What we're doing to Hyun-su,
is it right?
He didn't harm anyone. We aren't sure
if he'll turn into a monster.
-Locking him up like that--
-It isn't right.
I know, but Hyun-su is dangerous.
He's dangerous, but we need him.
ROOM 702 SUNSCREEN
ROOM 1009 DOG FOOD, CHARGER, SANITARY PADS
Damn, why's he only on my case?
Well…
It's sad to see it go to waste.
Plus, we need the bottle. So…
You're so immature.
When do you think Hyun-su will be back?
I don't know. He's late today.
-Do you think something happened to him?
-You know he doesn't die.
Even if he gets hurt,
he gets better after a nap.
-Where is it?
-Where?
Come here!
-It's going to come this way.
-Hurry.
-Let's go.
-Now!
What is it?
-Hold this.
-Oh God.
It's my husband.
I have to do this.
-Wait.
-Stay still.
-No.
-Seon-yeong.
Seon-yeong.
Pull yourself together, Kim Seok-hyeon.
Kim Seok-hyeon.
Pull yourself together!
You're back.
Do you have any last words?
Please…
kill…
me…
And…
You'll end up like this, too.
EXIT
You said it for the first time
in 30 years.
I'm sorry…
Why did it have to be now?
JULY 2020
Get the rescue kits.
Hurry!
I'm Seo Yi-kyung
from Sujeong Fire Station.
-Hurry!
-She's the bereaved family member.
-I'm sorry for your--
-His body…
hasn't been found.
Please give permission
to preserve the scene. I'll find it.
I cannot give permission.
You're a firefighter, so you know…
LETTER OF RESIGNATION
Move! That way!
From now on, I'm just the bereaved.
-You must find him at all costs.
-Yi-kyung!
DO NOT CROSS
UNDER INVESTIGATION
DONGBU PENITENTIARY CLINIC
ENTER PASSWORD
INCORRECT PASSWORD
YOU ARE INVITED TO OUR WEDDING
THERE IS NO INTERNET CONNECTION
NOTES
MEDICAL RECORDS (YEAR 2020)
HOSPITAL STATISTICAL DATA
CRUCRU EXQA
It's not a disease. It's a curse.
I was consumed by it, too.
It's been ten days since I began
to have nosebleeds and fainting spells.
They talk to me and ask questions,
but I'm still resisting them.
I have to be a subject myself
and solve this phenomenon.
Fifteen days.
Subjects enter a stable period
after 15 days.
If I hold out
for five more days,
I'll become a special infectee.
One thing is for sure.
Studying someone who survives
the monsterization symptoms
is the only method we have.
It's the last hope to end
this nightmarish disaster.
The power is out.
Let's wait a little, Ji-eun.
It'll be okay.
How do you know?
It's obviously not okay.
What's going to happen now?
I hear we're almost out of food.
The water will be cut off soon.
I'm scared.
Su-yeong,
are we going to die?
It's over.
We're all doomed!
I really hope I go to Heaven after I die.
So?
So what?
Do you want to commit mass suicide
since we'll all die soon?
Stop whining!
Whining won't change anything.
It's okay.
People are getting agitated.
I know.
It's sooner than I expected.
Electricity has no direct impact
on survival.
Having no drinking water
is a more serious problem.
You must be happy
because you're so cool-headed.
Be honest with me.
Do you think we can survive?
What are you?
I don't know.
What?
I don't know what I am.
You can just start over here.
You can live however you want.
And if I reveal my desire,
I become a monster?
That's right. Now tell me what you want.
Fuck you.
Fine.
Good luck, then.
BASTARD
Are you up?
I knew you were a pushover.
Being a doormat is in your blood.
But I was wondering, Hyun-su.
Who did that?
-I did.
-I mean,
why did you do it?
Because of me.
It's not because of you, moron.
Does it make you feel better
to think that way?
That's why everyone blames you.
You have to throw
a huge fucking fit
to make people understand.
Doesn't it hurt?
No.
You were groaning miserably earlier.
I don't know where you were hurt,
so stick these on yourself.
I don't need them.
-I'll recover--
-Make it obvious.
"I got hurt because of you.
It fucking hurts!"
Get it?
Why don't you get it?
BAND-AID
Leave him alone.
If it's that important, you go yourself.
-Stop.
-Hey!
You're the worst.
You act like you care,
but you just stand by and do nothing.
-You're no different.
-What about you?
All you do is run your mouth.
You fucking bitch.
Hey, Eun-yu.
Stay out of it.
You aren't even my real brother.
You're fucking unbelievable.
DO NOT ENTER
We have to go outside.
There's no guarantee we'll be safe here.
Nothing happened
when we retrieved the corpses.
The situation might've calmed down.
So?
It's…
taking you longer and longer to recover.
We don't know
when you'll turn into a monster.
You think…
I'll hurt you guys if I become a monster?
There are monsters that don't hurt people.
So?
Can you be sure you'll be like them?
A monster is a monster.
We don't have time.
We must find a way to survive
while you can still resist.
I don't expect you to understand.
Just do your job.
You're just being used.
You'll end up like this, too.
Tell me.
Where is Sang-won?
No.
What did you do to him?
You're not in a position to ask questions.
Tell me!
You read this. He must be dead.
Whether he killed himself or got killed.
I HAVE TO BE A SUBJECT MYSELF
AND SOLVE THIS PHENOMENON.
Even if he's not dead,
I don't think you could say he's alive.
Now it's my turn to ask.
What and how much do you know?
I know you'll kill me.
Why do you think so?
If I know too much, you'll kill me
to shut me up.
If I know nothing, you'll kill me
because I'm useless.
But…
I have to live no matter what.
How?
Get a grip.
You're looking for someone
resisting monsterization, right?
I know where one is.
I think it's asleep.
Let's not wake it up.
Help!
-Mr. Han!
-Su-yeong, it's dangerous!
Run!
Mr. Han!
BASED ON SWEET HOME
BY CARNBY KIM AND YOUNGCHAN HWANG
Subtitle translation by Soo-hyun Yang
Modify by Blue-Bird™